(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.0b2",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 6,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 1000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
MORI CALLIOPE BIRTHDAY LIVE
[Title: Mori Calliope Birthday Live]
AZKi
[Guest: AZKi]
NERISSA RAVENCROFT
[Guest: Nerissa Ravencroft]
TOKINO SORA
[Guest: Tokino Sora]
HOSHIMACHI SUISEI
[Guest: Hoshimachi Suisei]
MORI CALLIOPE
UNCUT ROCK!! FEAT. LIVE BAND!
MORI CALLIOPE 6TH BIRTHDAY CONCERT
[Title: Uncut Rock!! Mori Calliope 6th Birthday Concert]
Rivals and Equals
[Song: Rivals and Equals]
Base instincts take control
Like primal ways of a warrior
Is it glory you're after, like me?
Underestimated everywhere I turn
Taking aim but it doesn't make a difference at all
I got a million different enemies I cannot recall
You're rocking up to a battle when you know that you'll fall
Hidden motivation, watch it all burn
I gotta tell you
I never liked you
Now would I lie to you?
Let me ignite you
When thunder crashes down
When the world caves under my pressure
There'll be no one to save
Where is your pride, your human will to survive?
Was it just
Empty words for your grave?
I reach inside this soul
Now all that remains
Is delusion and decay
Cuz of you, I live this way
We're not rivals
We're not equals
You're just confused
Lightning never strikes twice in the same spot
So go ahead and run up on me till you get your shot
I see the weapon that you're hiding, come on ready or not
Another life and you would never give a second thought
Hello, みなさん！
Hello, everyone!
Yeah yeah! Woo! This is... whoa, thank you!
This is Mori Calliope, 森カリオペです。
This is Mori Calliope, I'm Mori Calliope.
Thank you so much everybody for coming to my birthday live!
Here is the hashtag, #UNCUTROCK, right here, right here, right here.
Check it out, everybody!
Today's theme is obviously birthday, right? It's my birthday!
And so, if you look behind us, we've got stones!
Oh my god! What kind of stones, I wonder?
Maybe... birthday stones? Depending on the guest, I suppose.
Mori Calliope is diamond.
So, of course, you will see white behind me.
Yes, and the idea is to sing original songs with guests,
and also my own songs.
And I'm looking at the comments right now. Now the show isn't very high quality,
so there's like a pretty big lag, but I'm looking. Woo! Woo!
Phew, there's a lot of clapping emojis. Holy cannoli!
Holy cannoli is right! こんばんは、こんばんは！
Holy cannoli is right! Good evening, good evening!
コメント見てます。
I'm looking at the comments.
Wow, すごい！ "Happy birthday", "happy birthday".
Wow, amazing! "Happy birthday", "happy birthday".
Happy birthday wishes, ありがとうございます！
Happy birthday wishes, thank you so much!
And you know what, behind me is not only stones,
but I also have a fabulous band joining me!
Yes, that's right! Live band!
Thank you so much to the band for coming.
Now, in particular, we have somebody that Calliope and I really respect.
Today, Park-san is here with us!
カリちゃん、Happy Birthday!
Calli-chan, happy birthday!
Thank you! 今日はよろしくお願いします！
Thank you! I'm looking forward to working with you today!
よろしくお願いします。
I'm looking forward to it as well.
Yeah, Park-san is one of my favorite bass players ever.
He's done two songs for me, in particular, Orpheus and Sepia.
OrpheusとSepiaのベースやってくれました。
He played the bass for Orpheus and Sepia.
Park-sanはすごいリスペクトしてます。はい！
I really respect Park-san. Yes!
But I have so many wonderful members in the band today,
and also guests as well, and I don't want to take up too much more time...
But anyway, we should probably sing with guests,
because I want to showcase all that we've been practicing too, together.
So, let's go ahead and begin!
The first... the first guest, come on!
I can't control myself
[On-screen: I can't control myself]
歪な世界　微かに聞こえる音
In a distorted world, a sound heard faintly
世界で二人　切り取ったようで
It's as if just the two of us were cut away from the world
届きそうな手　すれ違った心
Hands that almost reached, hearts that passed each other by
ちょっと痛むんだ
It hurts a little
ここで待って
Wait here
決められないままで
Still unable to decide
戸惑いに溢れてしまうよ
I'm overflowing with confusion
もう何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it so many times now
零れた想いを数えて
Counting the spilled emotions
もう何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it so many times now
世界　世界
World, world
開くのを待っている
Waiting for it to open
歪な世界　回り続ける針は
In a distorted world, the hands that keep turning
千切れた意識　繋いでいく
Connect the torn consciousness
刻んだ金属　鳴り響く心に
In the carved metal and my echoing heart
ちょっと響くんだ
It echoes a little
ここで待って
Wait here
君を繋げ
Connect you
決められないままで戸惑い 溢れて しまうよ
Without being able to decide, bewilderment overflows.
もう何度も繰り返した
I've already repeated it many times.
神様に願いをかけて
I offered my prayers to God,
何度も繰り返した
repeating them over and over.
世界 世界 開くのを待っている
The world, the world... I'm waiting for it to open.
もうなんにも いらないから
Because I don't need anything anymore...
零れた想いは幻
those spilled thoughts were but an illusion.
もう何度も繰り返した
I've already repeated it many times.
神様に願いを かけて何度も繰り返して
Praying to God, I repeated it many times.
世界 世界 開くのを待っている
The world, the world... I'm waiting for it to open.
イェーイ！
Yeaaaah!
最初のゲストはAZKi先輩です！
Our first guest is AZKi-senpai!
AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートにゼロゲッサー、
Mic in my right hand, map in my left, I'm the GeoGuessr of your heart,
カリオペちゃん、ハッピーバースデー！
Calliope-chan, Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！Birthday Desu! 誕生日です！
Thank you so much! It's my birthday! It really is!
誕生日カル！
Birthday Calli!
ありがとうございます。さっき一緒に歌った曲大好きです！
Thank you. I absolutely love the song we just sang!
ありがとうございます！なんとAZKiのオリジナル曲を一緒に歌わせていただきました！
Thank you! We actually just performed one of AZKi's original songs together!
そうですよね。ずっとバンドアレンジ聴きたかったから選びました！
That's right. I've always wanted to hear it with a band arrangement, so I chose it!
めっちゃ熱かったです！
It was so intense!
やった！
We did it!
楽しかったよね。
That was so much fun.
バンドの演奏も凄かったです！
The band's performance was incredible too!
ありがとうございます！イェーイ！
Thank you! Yay!
ちなみにステージと見てほしい。
By the way, I want everyone to look at the stage.
いや凄い！めちゃくちゃピカピカ光ってる！
Whoa, it's amazing! It's sparkling so much!
ぴかぴかストーン！
Sparkling stones!
そうだよね。素敵ですよね。素敵なステージです！
Right? It's lovely. It's a wonderful stage!
ちなみにAZKi先輩の誕生石は知ってる？
By the way, do you know AZKi-senpai's birthstone?
AZKiの誕生石は... 7月なんですけど、ルビー！ルビー、この色！
AZKi's birthstone... I was born in July, so it's Ruby! Like this color!
なりました！凄い！
It changed! Awesome!
こっち色が変わるんですね今日は。
The colors are actually changing here today.
凄い！めっちゃ赤です！
Wow! It's so red!
そうですね。きれい！
It is. So beautiful!
すごくきれいから一緒に何かあの写真撮りたいと思います！
Since it's so pretty, I'd love to take a photo together!
撮りたい！
I want to!
撮りたい！せっかく。
Me too! Since we're here.
Take screenshots!
いい感じです！イェーイ！
Looking good! Yay!
イェーイイェーイイェーイ！ありがとうございます。
Yay yay yay! Thank you so much.
じゃ、まあ生ライブだからやっぱ水飲みたいと思う。
Well, since it's a live concert, I think I need some water.
水は飲もう！
Let's drink some water!
Yes, 水乾杯です！
Yes, a water toast!
はい、ども乾杯！
Yes, cheers everyone!
Cheers! Cheers!
Okay okay. やった！次の曲。
Okay, okay. We did it! Now for the next song.
お！次の曲は何だろうな？
Oh! I wonder what the next song will be?
もう一曲ありますよね、一緒に。
We have one more song to do together, right?
あります！そう。そうですね。
We do! That's right.
さっきAZKi先輩のオリ曲歌いましたね。今回はカリオペのオリ曲です。
We sang AZKi's original before. This time it's Calliope's original song.
歌わせていただきます。
We're going to perform it for you now.
The next song is Calliope's original, "未来島 ～Future Island～"!
The next song is Calliope's original, "Future Island"!
危険な海に浮かぶ島 Head head
An island floating in a dangerous sea, head head.
世界変える未来島のLove call
A love call from Future Island that'll change the world.
最高の知能 叶えるよ願望
The ultimate intellect will grant your every wish.
未来のお宝探しちゃおう
Let's go search for the treasures of the future.
天才が引き起こす発想の奇跡
A miracle of inspiration brought about by a genius.
脳内で終わらせない夢のファンタジー
A dream fantasy that won't just end in your mind.
世界がひっくり返るテクノロジー
Technology that'll turn the world upside down.
大体叶えちゃうラボラトリー
A laboratory that can grant almost anything.
釈迦　リリス　エジソン　ピタゴラス
Shaka, Lilith, Edison, Pythagoras...
アトラス　欲　独人のサテライト
Atlas, York, the satellites of a lone man.
湧き出すアイデア止まらない
Bubbling ideas that just won't stop.
忙しすぎて猫の手も借りたい
I'm so busy I'd even take a cat's help.
海も何も超えてゆく海賊を
Admiring the pirates who cross the seas and beyond,
常識超えてゆく発明を
and the inventions that defy common sense.
あんな奴らに憧れてきた
I've always looked up to people like them.
次は誰が王になる？
Who will be the next one to become king?
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, the wisdom of the future.
閃きを巻き起こせ
Stir up a flash of inspiration!
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, the wisdom of the future.
過去も世界も飛び越して
Leaping beyond the past and the world.
MEGAPUNK 生み出すよアイデア
MEGAPUNK, creating ideas.
MEGAPUNK...
レッツゴー
Let's go
革命をここから
Revolution starts from here
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
メキメキ
Mekimeki
革命をここから
Revolution starts from here
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
危険な海に浮かぶ島...
An island floating in dangerous seas...
世界を変える未来島、LOVE IT！
A future island that changes the world, love it!
This mind is undefeated,
Until my goal's completed.
Let's keep on searching for the treasure of to come.
Genius! A miracle, a deity gotta set it free.
Science! Fantastic dreams are burning up inside of me.
Experience! I'll turn the world around with new technology.
Future! A laboratory cast upon the sea.
Poisoned to evil and the contents of mind
Right into knowledge greedy by a learned satellite
Ideas can't stop rushing out, stop thinking they might
Could use a hand, at too busy working into the night
The pirate king who braves the ocean while in search of elation
A ruler of invention that can modify your reason
Once washed in jealousy, someday I've gotta be
Fixed on the throne, I know what I've gotta do
無限の夢 未知の知へ
Towards infinite dreams and unknown knowledge
煌めきを巻き起こせ
Whip up a sparkling sensation
無限の夢 未知の知へ
Towards infinite dreams and unknown knowledge
過去も世界も飛び越して
Leaping over the past and the world
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
海の頭脳アイデア
The sea's brain, Idea
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
トゥルットゥルットゥルッ
Turu-turu-turu
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
革命をここから
Revolution starts from here
ベガパンク！
Vegapunk!
言う事聞かなきゃ振りかざす 正義
If you don't listen, I'll brandish justice
世界守る軍団の 正義
The justice of the army protecting the world
秘密巡る怪しい企み
Suspicious schemes surrounding secrets
過去の記憶に隠された狂気
Madness hidden in memories of the past
真実を秘めた勇気
Courage harboring the truth
謎に満ちたその夢のエネルギー
That dream's energy, filled with mystery
天才が見せる世界の形
The shape of the world the genius reveals
ここは未来の島へ
This is toward the future island
Thank you Egghead! Bye-bye! See later!
[Dancing Reed]
[Song: Dancing Reed]
All right! Whoo!
Everybody welcome to the stage, Sora-senpai!
Happy birthday! Yes!
ドキドキ 演じたいけど
I want to perform with a racing heart,
冗談なら笑えないよ
but if it's a joke, I can't laugh.
渋滞 曖昧 どっち向くの？
Congestion and ambiguity—which way do we face?
蜃気楼に手を伸ばした
I reached out to a mirage.
いつの世も 夢物語
In any era, it's just a dream story;
そんな光は 目隠しにして
turn such light into a blindfold.
騒めく 鼓動 招き入れないで
Don't invite the buzzing heartbeat in;
幻じゃ嫌だよ 私を奪って
I don't want it to be an illusion. Take me away.
魅惑のダンシング
Enchanting dancing,
止まない色気 収まらない熱
unstoppable charm, uncontainable heat.
君の情緒は 私の信頼の証拠
Your emotions are proof of my trust.
書き換えちゃうかも 責任重大ね
I might rewrite them; a heavy responsibility.
一切合切 デンス・デンス・デンス・ウィア・ダンシング
Everything, dance dance dance, we are dancing.
宙になって 此処身を任せて ゼログラビティ
Become the air, leave yourself here—zero gravity.
ヤ・バ・バ・バ デンス・デンス・デンス・ジャスト・ア・デンス
Ya-ba-ba-ba, dance dance dance, just a dance,
ジャスト・ア・デンス 声は闇に熱を灯すの
just a dance. Voices light up heat in the dark.
目を覚ましても離れないで
Don't leave me, even if I wake up.
メイビー ニーディー 正気じゃないのよ
Maybe needy, I'm not in my right mind;
体温が忘れられない
I can't forget your body heat.
だぁれ かぁれ そんなんじゃないから
Who or whom—it's not like that,
独り占めして ユーフォリア
so keep it all to yourself—Euphoria.
禁止命令 上書きして
Overwrite the prohibition order.
迷宮の世には 流せない
In this labyrinth world, things can't flow.
寂幕 毒と偽りだって
Even if it's loneliness, poison, or lies,
隠し切れない ゾーニング
zoning can't be hidden away.
私に構って 狂い出す クレイジー・クレイジー・ラブ
Pay attention to me, going mad—crazy crazy love.
魔天楼から 連れ去らって
Take me away from the skyscraper.
君の表情は 私の心酔の証
Your expression is proof of my intoxication.
塗り替えちゃいなよ 責任重大ね
Go ahead and repaint it; a heavy responsibility.
過ぎ去ったネオン残像 シューティングスター
The neon afterimage that passed by—shooting star.
グライダー みたいに 漂えば
If I drift along like a glider,
虚妄も何処もなかった
there was no falsehood or anywhere else.
指先で待った 君を探している
Waiting at my fingertips, I'm looking for you.
その声を聞かせて
Let me hear that voice.
私に構って！
Pay attention to me!
教えてよ恋の先を！
Tell me what lies beyond love!
拡がって収まんない Universe
Expanding, won't fit, universe
君の存在は
Your existence
私の将来までも
has stepped into my future too
踏み込んだのよ 付き合ってよね
Go out with me
一切合切Dance Dance Dance
Everything, dance, dance, dance,
We Are Dancing Reed
夢中になって絡み合った
Entangled in being lost,
ゼログラビティ
zero gravity
構わずDance Dance Dance
Without caring, dance, dance, dance,
Just a Dance Just a Dance
声は闇に預けたまま
Leaving my voice in the darkness
目を覚ましても離れないで
Don't let me go even if I wake up
Yes, our second guest is Sora-senpai!
はいみんな、こんそめ！ときのそらです！
Hi everyone! Kon-Sora! Tokino Sora here!
カリちゃん、ハッピーバースデー！
Calli-chan, happy birthday!
Thank you!
そら大先輩、ありがとうございます！ずっと一緒に歌いたかったから。
Sora-senpai, thank you so much! I've always wanted to sing with you.
あ、本当ですか？ありがとう！
Oh, really? Thank you!
嬉しいですよマジで！やったー！ヘイヘイヘイ！
I'm so happy, seriously! Yay! Hey hey hey!
ヘイヘイ！
Hey hey!
かわいいよね！すごいたくさん踊りました。
You're so cute! I danced a lot!
あ、本当だね！
Oh, we sure did!
いいわ、アイドルわーお！ドキドキ！
Nice, idol wow! Doki doki!
ドキドキ！
Doki doki!
Yes! X trending number 3 in Japan!
Thank you so much! It's trending number 3 in Japan!
あ、おめでとう！トレンド、やったー！
Oh, congratulations! Trending, yay!
やったー！ありがとう！たくさん使ってね。
Yay! Thank you! Please use the tag a lot.
Please hashtag! Please!
Thank you so much, ah, I'm so happy! ありがとう！
Thank you so much, ah, I'm so happy! Thank you!
イェーイ！そして今回、大好きな曲一緒に歌いました。
Yay! And this time, we sang a song I love together.
Dancing Reed!
Wow, すごいなんかパーティハッピーですよ。大好き。
Wow, it's like a party, happy, right? I love it.
ダンサブル！
Danceable!
めっちゃ良かった！そら先輩、エメラルド来た！
It was so good! Sora-senpai, Emerald came!
ねー、綺麗！緑！
Right? Beautiful! Green!
お誕生日月ですよね、誕生石ですよね？
It's your birthday month, so it's your birthstone, right?
さあ、5月の誕生石エメラルドです。
Yes, May's birthstone is Emerald.
Emerald! おー、すごい良い発音！Nice English! Very good!
Emerald! Wow, such good pronunciation! Nice English! Very good!
あ、本当？ありがとう！
Oh, really? Thank you!
そうですよね。ちなみに、写真撮ろうか？
That's right. By the way, shall we take a photo?
あ、撮る！Let's do it!
Oh, let's! Let's do it!
イェーイ！いいっすねー。
Yay! Nice!
イェーイ！この写真もアップしてね、X。
Yay! Upload this photo to X too!
よろしくねー！
Please do!
よろしくね！楽しい！じゃあ、水飲みましょう。
Please do! Fun! Now, let's drink some water.
水！乾杯！
Water! Cheers!
乾杯！
Cheers!
飲んだほうがいいっすよね。
Better to drink, right?
そうね、水は大事。
Yes, water is important.
そうだよー。楽しい、生ライブ！
That's right. Live is so fun!
楽しいね！
Fun, isn't it?
もう一曲、一緒に歌いたいんですけど、大丈夫ですか？
I want to sing one more song with you, is that okay?
もちろん！
Of course!
Let's do it, okay!
Now everyone, please listen to this next song.
You'll understand why I chose it, because Sora-senpai is in the PV for this song.
Please enjoy my original song, Dawn Blue!
掴まえて ほら この瞬間さ
Catch it, look, this is the moment
A world of affection awaits
Dawn Blue
[Song: Dawn Blue]
ずっと同じ毎日に 迷いがあっても
Even if there's hesitation in the same everyday life,
気付かない振りをしていたんだ
I was pretending not to notice.
あのちょっとの勇気が まだ出せなくて
I couldn't yet find that little bit of courage,
まどろみの中で 彷徨っていた
and I was wandering in a slumber.
夜空に浮かぶ 星に願いをかけるんだ
I'll make a wish on a star floating in the night sky.
I hope 抱いてる夢を 絶対諦めたくない
I hope... I never want to give up on the dream I hold.
走り出すから
Because I'm starting to run.
追いかけて 今 あの瞬間さ
Chasing it now, this is the moment.
見たことのないストーリー 進んでいくんだ
A story I've never seen before is moving forward.
いつの日にかきっと 描いた世界へ
So that someday I can surely...
辿り着けるように
reach the world I envisioned.
Let go of the days of traumatic sorrow
That let goes onto tomorrow's rolling
If this is how the story goes
To find that strength inside, I'll remember why back then
You took my hand, and you said...
つかまえて、ほら この shooting star
Catch it, look, this shooting star
さあ、まずは一歩 踏み出して 恐れずにゆこう
Now, let's take that first step and go without fear
いつの日にかきっと
Someday for sure
まだ見ぬ世界へ 辿り着けるように
So we can reach a world yet unseen
夜明けに咲いた月が
The moon that bloomed at dawn
眩い ブルーの 空に溶けてく
Melts into the dazzling blue sky
You and I, an undecided future,
Doesn't matter if the final truth hurts
もうすぐ 朝が 動き出すから
Because morning will soon start moving
抱きしめて今 この shooting star
Hold it tight now, this shooting star
見たことのないストーリー
A story never seen before
I'll be here betting on that
Fearsome heart
Cuz you're that shooting star
It's hopeless now, but maybe if you take that step
Into the darkness, you'll find me
Running by your side until the dawn
In the end, it's you and me
Us against tomorrow
Face the world that we had dreamed
Dry your eyes, and don't look back.
Thank you so much Sora-senpai! Mata issho ni utaimashou!
Thank you so much Sora-senpai! Let's sing together again!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
Thank you!
Bye-bye! またね！
Bye-bye! See you!
See you!
うわあ、楽しいね、生ライブ！
Wow, live shows are fun, aren't they?
Oh man, this is so fun. I just love singing.
I love singing live so much, and you guys, thank you for being a part of it.
Woo! Nailed it, you think so?
Because Sora-senpai was by my side. It was awesome.
Now next, I'll be singing with a surprise secret guest, but...
...it's a bit of a break for myself and the band right now because...
...we're going to go back in time to a time when I recorded something with a special guest...
...with the power of technology. You'll understand what I mean but...
...let's go back in the past, and myself and the band are going to chill for a minute.
So please enjoy that special guest performance and I'll see you guys soon...
...for the next live one very shortly. Okay.
See you then. どうぞ！
See you then. Go ahead!
罪と蜜 (feat. Mori Calliope)
[Title: Sin and Honey (feat. Mori Calliope)]
そう恋に落ちたんだけどきっと不幸に堕ちたんだ
Yeah, I fell in love, but I surely fell into misfortune
気づきゃ僕らは行為に及んでいた
Before I knew it, we were performing the act
アナタの策 故意によるものだったんだ
It was your scheme, something done on purpose
見事さ地獄への片道切符
Splendid, a one-way ticket to hell
理性奪い去るリップ
Lips that snatch away reason
妄想 高揚 本能 暴走 So Mellow
Delusion, exaltation, instinct, rampage, so mellow
さながら脳に数枚のチップ
Just like several chips in the brain
埋め込む様な狂愛のキス
A kiss of mad love that feels like embedding them
“アタシ アタシ アタシ アタシ アタシ アタシの永久のVIP”
"I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm your eternal VIP"
囁いた言葉ずっと離れずに
The whispered words never leaving me
アナタにアナタにアナタに相応しいヒトになれますか？
Can I become a person worthy of you, you, you?
Right you Left me 愛すyou
So we did it did it did it did it
Right you Left me, love you
Stop
I love you my girl
I love you my boy
アナタを知って全ては過去になる
Knowing you, everything becomes the past
I love you my girl
I love you my boy
しあーせに満ちた未来を作ろうね
Let's create a future full of happiness
そう愛し切ってどうかこんな僕を
Yeah, love me completely, please, someone like me
愛し切ってどうかこんなアタシを
Love me completely, please, someone like me
Give me Give me Give me Give me LOVE
ねぇアタシに退屈を着せないで
Hey, don't make me wear boredom
とびきりのドレスとアナタのエスコートで
With an extraordinary dress and your escort
赤く染まる絨毯の上歩く
Walking on the red-stained carpet
マムシじゃないけどアタシはスター
I'm not a pit viper, but I'm a star
世界で一番のお姫様
The number one princess in the world,
いくよ 3 2 1
here we go, 3, 2, 1.
だけど アナタには見せてあげる
But I'll show you...
ママに内緒 インダス 薔薇のタトゥー
Keep it a secret from Mom - the Indus rose tattoo.
口移し流し込む 罪の味
The taste of sin poured from my lips to yours.
共犯ね これでアナタは
We're accomplices now; with this, you...
アタシに
to me,
相応しいヒトになりました
have become the person I deserve.
Right you Left me
愛すyou
I love you.
So we did it did it did it did it
Stop
I love you my girl
I love you my boy
裏表 アナタ僕 罪と蜜
Two sides of a coin, you and I, sin and honey.
I love you my girl
I love you my boy
その味知る前には戻れない
I can't go back to before I knew that taste.
そう愛してみて
So try loving me,
どうかこんな僕を
please, love someone like me.
愛してみて
Try loving me,
どうかこんなアタシを
please, love someone like me.
Give me Give me Give me Give me LOVE
Everybody!
Alright!
みなさん！
Everyone!
Welcome syudouさんとカリオペ3D Birthday Live!
Welcome syudou and Calliope's 3D Birthday Live!
Thank you!
Check it out!
壊し合う様に 癒し合う様に
As if breaking each other, as if healing each other,
求め合ってしまうのよ しょうがないじゃない
we end up wanting each other; I just can't help it.
与えられた天国より 選んだ地獄を
Rather than a gifted heaven, I choose a hell
アナタと2人 奈落まで
with you, all the way to the abyss.
I love you my girl
I love you my boy
ただ堕ちていく
just falling down.
I love you my girl
I love you my boy
アナタを知って全ては過去になる
Knowing you, everything becomes the past.
I love you my girl
I love you my boy
しあーせに満ちた未来を作ろうね
Let's create a future filled with happiness.
そう愛し切って
So love me completely,
どうかこんな僕を
please, love someone like me.
愛し切って
Love me completely,
どうかこんなアタシを
please, love someone like me.
Give me Give me Give me Give me LOVE
そう愛し合ってしまったこんな僕ら
We who have ended up loving each other so much,
ハッピーエンドに別れを告げ
saying farewell to a happy ending,
Give me Give me Give me Give me LOVE
みなさん、どう思いましたか？
Everyone, what did you think?
ありがとうございます！楽しかった〜
Thank you so much! That was fun!
イエイイエイ、スーパースペシャルゲスト、syudouさんが来ました！
Yay yay! Our super special guest, syudou-san is here!
こんにちは！Dead Beatsのみなさんこんにちは、syudouです。
Hello! Hello everyone, Dead Beats, I'm syudou.
はい、自己紹介お願いします！
Yes, please introduce yourself!
はい、僕はですね、ミュージシャンやってますsyudouでございます。
Yes, well, I'm syudou, and I'm a musician.
そして、ハッピーバースデーカリオペさん！おめでとうございます。
And, Happy Birthday Calliope-san! Congratulations.
あ、サンキュー！ありがとう！
Oh, thank you! Thanks!
ライブも最高です。
The live performance is amazing too.
あ、ちなみにハイタッチしたいんですが…あ、いきますか？
Ah, by the way, I'd like to do a high-five... Oh, shall we?
いきますか？よし…せーの！
Shall we? Okay... ready, set!
よいしょ！イエイ！ありがとうございます。
There! Yay! Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます。イエイ。ちなみにsyudouさんは、ま音楽活動色々やってますね？
Thank you. Yay. By the way, syudou-san, you're involved in various musical activities, right?
どんな活動やってますか？
What kind of activities do you do?
そうですね、僕はあのボカロPですね、ボーカロイドで楽曲を作ったり、
Well, I'm a Vocaloid P, making songs with Vocaloid,
シンガーソングライターとして歌を歌わせていただいたり、
I sing as a singer-songwriter,
そして色んな方に楽曲を提供させていただいたり、そんな活動させていただいております。
and I also provide songs to various artists; that's the kind of work I do.
イエイ！もちろんアタシ知ってるけど、なんか、大ファンだからね。
Yay! Of course I know, but I'm just such a big fan.
嬉しいです。ライブも以前来ていただきましたね。
I'm happy to hear that. You've also come to my lives before.
そうですね！武道館ライブめっちゃ楽しかった！
That's right! The Budokan live was so much fun!
いや、ありがとうございます。ホント僕も楽しくて、めちゃくちゃ盛り上がったんで、
Ah, thank you. I also had a blast, it was so exciting,
はい、嬉しいです今日出られて。はい。
so I'm really happy to be able to appear today. Yes.
こちらこそ、アタシもすごい嬉しいですね。ありがとうございます。
The pleasure is all mine, I'm also very happy. Thank you so much.
あの…このステージ、どう思いますか？
Um... what do you think of this stage?
ね、これすごいですよね。後ろからこの高さも含めて。
Yeah, this is incredible. Especially with the height from the back.
僕ちょっと高い所苦手なんで落ちないように気をつけながらやらないとなと思うんですけども、最高ですこれ。はい。
I'm a bit afraid of heights, so I have to be careful not to fall, but this is the best. Truly.
まかなり高いけど気をつけてね。
It's quite high, so please be careful.
ちょっと高いですよね、はい。下見えないから、やべ。
It really is high, yeah. I can't even see the bottom, it's scary.
え、でも、まそういえば、なんか、テーマが誕生日だから…
Oh, but, speaking of which, since the theme is birthday...
ちょっと知りたいね、syudouさんの誕生日はいつですか？
I'm a bit curious, when is your birthday, syudou-san?
僕の誕生日9月ですね。September.
My birthday is in September.
September! Septemberですね。
September! September, then.
お、Septemberのbirthday stone、誕生石はサファイアです。
Oh, September's birthstone is sapphire.
もほら、ステージはサファイア、サファイア、サファイアです！
Look, the stage is sapphire, sapphire, sapphire!
あ！そういうことだったんですかこれ。あ！なるほど！
Oh! So that's what this was. Ah! I see!
僕に合わせていただいてありがとう…たまたまですけど、あの服もこの青で、帽子も青であったんで、
Thank you for matching it to me... it's a coincidence, but my clothes and hat are also blue,
うわ！相性がいい！
wow! What a great match!
めっちゃ嬉しそうですね。ありがとうございます。
You seem really happy. Thank you very much.
やった！すごい、めっちゃいい感じですね。
Yatta! Great, it feels really good.
いいですね。嬉しいです。Wow.
It's good. I'm happy. Wow.
え、次の曲は、syudouさんが書き下ろしてくれたやつですね？
Um, the next song is the one you wrote for me, right?
そうですね。あの僕がすごいカリオペさんの楽曲大好きなんですけども、
That's right. I really love your songs, Calliope-san,
カリオペさんのこうカッコよくて、強くて、すごい美しいみたいなところを引き出せるような楽曲として作らせていただいた曲でございますね。はい。
and I wrote this song to bring out your coolness, strength, and incredible beauty. Yes.
ありがとう！や、めっちゃいい曲ホントに。なんか、大好きな曲だから。
Thank you! Yeah, it's a really good song, truly. It's one of my favorites.
嬉しいありがとうございます。
I'm glad, thank you very much.
マジホントに感謝してます。ありがとうございます。
I'm really, truly grateful. Thank you.
今回一緒に歌いたいと思います。
I'd like to sing it together this time.
初めてですね、一緒に歌うのはこれはね。
This will be the first time we sing it together, won't it?
初めてですね。
The first time.
なかなかレアなのではないでしょうか。
Isn't it quite a rare occasion?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you ready?
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you.
Okay、じゃ次の曲に行く前に、みんなに伝えたいことありますか？
Okay, before we move to the next song, is there anything you want to say to everyone?
はい、えそうですね、僕こうカリオペさんと何度かコラボさせていただいてるんですけども、
Yes, well, I've collaborated with Calliope-san several times now,
Dead Beatsのみなさん含めホントにあのアたたかく迎えていただいて、えすごい嬉しいです。
and everyone, including the Dead Beats, has really welcomed me warmly, which makes me very happy.
で今回ライブもこうやってやらせていただいて、みんなと一緒に盛り上がって…
And being able to do this live as well, and getting excited together with everyone...
...あれば嬉しいです。そして改めて
...I'd be happy. And again,
カリオペさん呼んでくれてありがとうございます。
thank you for inviting me, Calliope-san.
いえいえ、こちらこそ！
Not at all, the pleasure is mine!
じゃあ、それで聴いてくださいね。でもシウドウさん、紹介してください！
Then, please listen to this. But syudou-san, please introduce it!
はい。
Yes.
それではお聴きください、LET'S JUST CRASH！
Then please listen, LET'S JUST CRASH!
Hey hey 皆さん！
Hey hey everyone!
Yeah!
Let's go!
Ha-ha-ha-ha! Hey! Hey!
Hey, you got eyes and ears, but you don't look or listen
In other words, you're useless, every last one of ya
And that's why I'm gonna send you all to hell
All of humanity, hell!
声援背負い颯爽と登場 そういうんじゃねぇ
Riding high on cheers, that's not how I roll
I'm just the type you'd forget so don't waste your time
千切れ腐りかけの chain, going insane, somebody's gotta pay
Fraying, rotting chains, going insane, somebody's gotta pay
While I live with the pain, laugh at me now, I'm the one you can't tame, huh
低俗で最低の天才 そういうんでいい
A vulgar, bottom-tier genius, that's fine by me
想いが募る 場所に花は咲くから
Flowers will bloom where feelings gather
(Let's riot!)
(Get back, you're trash)
掃き溜めで希望を
In the dumpster, hope is
(Let's just crash)
積み上げていくんだ 頂から高らかに笑え
piling up; laugh loudly from the summit
(Lose control)
美しき理想を
The beautiful ideals
(Heads will roll)
汚してくる野郎は
The bastards who try to soil them,
誰だ一体？誰だ一体？誰だったとしても
who are they? who are they? No matter who it is,
この理想は無理だろって
even if someone says this ideal is impossible,
誰が言ったとしても叶えてこうぜ
let's make it come true anyway
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Woah! Bye!
Yeah, get, verse 2...
Listen.
正解不正解の解答 どうだっていい
Correct or incorrect answers, I don't care
そんなとっくのとうに 超えた場所に俺は立っている
I'm standing in a place beyond all that long ago
Yeah, meaningless problems, everybody's got 'em
And they can't be satisfied until somebody's at the bottom, so what?
You think you're special 'cause you got some grit and hunger?
We ain't getting any younger, thinking let's just crash
心が通う 時に魂が叫ぶ
When hearts connect, the soul screams out
(Hoo-hoo!)
(Get back, you're trash)
ドブネズミの様に
Like a sewer rat,
(Let's just crash)
気高く生きるんだ 俺が通る今すぐに退け
living nobly; I'm coming through, move aside right now
(Let's riot!)
(Get back, you're trash)
掃き溜めで希望を
In the dumpster, hope is
(Let's just crash)
積み上げていくんだ 頂から高らかに笑え
piling up; laugh loudly from the summit
(Lose control)
美しき理想を
The beautiful ideals
(Heads will roll)
汚してくる野郎は
The bastards who try to soil them,
誰だ一体？誰だ一体？誰だったとしても
who are they? who are they? No matter who it is,
この理想は無理だろって
even if someone says this ideal is impossible,
誰が言ったとしても叶えてこうぜ
let's make it come true anyway
Oh-oh, woah-oh... Woah-oh-oh!
Come on! 3, 2, 1, let's go! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Wooh!
シウドウさんありがとうございました！
syudou-san, thank you very much!
Thank you guy-ope!
Yeah yeah!
叶えてこうぜ
Let's make it come true
でもまだまだ終わってないっすね皆さん！
But we're not done yet, everyone!
Alright!
LET'S JUST CRASH!
ありがとうございます！バイバイ、シウドウさん！
Thank you very much! Bye bye, syudou-san!
バイバイ！Thank you Dead Beats and カリオッペ！
Bye bye! Thank you Dead Beats and Calliope!
Yeah yeah, peace!
Ah 皆さん、that was so fun.
Ah everyone, that was so fun.
I really respect syudou-san as an artist.
He does a lot of his work himself for his songs,
you know, writes and composes and sings...
...and everything. He's really cool. Big ups!
But I think it is about time
that maybe we get back to the future? The present?
Where I'm performing with all my friends right now. Hmm, yes.
But that was a lot of fun.
Ah, as I thought. Right on time.
It looks like it's time for me to get back to the future
and go sing with all my friends again. Back in the present,
future... I don't know, it doesn't even make any sense. Let's go!
See you there!
Blue World. Lyrics: Nerissa Ravencroft. Music, Arrangement: 田中拓教
[Title: Blue World. Lyrics: Nerissa Ravencroft. Music, Arrangement: Hironori Tanaka]
Walking an empty road
Nowhere for me to go
No world
Lost and lonely
Yeah, it's only me
Burnt out like candlelight
Left blazing through the night
Melting slowly
Until nothing else is left of me
Colored in shades of gray
Watching the days pass in front of me
Longing to find a way
I can fly away
I'm drifting through this blue blue world
It's always been clear to me
How cruel the world can be
My shadow's the only one beside me
No love to call my own
No notice on my phone
Sunk in silence
Has engulfed the very life I lead
Colored in shades of gray
Watching the days pass in front of me
Memories I wish would stay
Always fade away
I'm looking in this blue blue world
Though my heart is torn
And my weary wings are worn
Just tonight
Can I dream
Of a better life
With happiness inside?
Colored in shades of gray
Watching my life pass in front of me
Maybe it's not too late
If I can't escape
I'll have to make my own way
Colored in shades of gray
Having it in hand
I can make a change
I'll try to find the strength
Take a breath and feign
Bring color to this blue blue world
Whoa! Beautiful, Nerissa! You're so great! Ah! Thank you for coming!
Thank you for having me!
After that emotional song, now we're all energetic!
Oh my god, hi everybody!
Happy birthday, Mori-san!
Happy birthday, Mori!
Oh! Thank you! Thank you! It is my birthday!
But who is this lovely lady I'm singing with right now?
Who could I be?
Hi darlings! This is Hololive English -Advent-'s devilish diva...
the one, the only, Nerissa Ravencroft...
here with you today at your birthday party!
Wow! かっこいい! So cool!
Wow! So cool! So cool!
ありがとうございます! Wow!
Thank you very much! Wow!
You're so awesome, Nerissa.
Thank you so much for letting me sing
your Shojo Meguro song together with you.
We both love Shojo Meguro!
We both have Shojo Meguro original songs!
Yes, we both do!
I'm happy that my first time performing it
got to be with you!
Yeah, no, seriously, it was so fun.
It's always fun singing with a friend,
so thank you for letting me be a part of it.
We got to harmonize, too!
Oh, yeah! I did my best to learn the harmonies...
...and, you know, try and remember and stay consistent.
You did amazing! You impressed me!
Thank you so much!
Well, I guess we gotta talk about your birthstone...
...because now we're gonna talk about your birthday
even though it's my birthday.
Do you know your birthstone's a topaz?
Yes! Oh, it's so pretty!
My birthday's November 21st, I'm a Scorpio,
and it's so pretty!
It matches my... hair, my hair...
...your little hairclip! So true!
Oh my gosh, it just positively lights you up,
you're glowing!
How about we take some pictures
in front of the stone?
Oh, yeah, let's do it! Let's do it!
All right, here we go.
Peace! Peace!
Dochi demo! Either one's good.
Either one's good!
Oh, facing each other! Be a little sexy.
Oh, boa...
Ii kanji! Very nice!
Very nice!
Use the hashtag! Yes, please!
Oh my gosh, please use the hashtag lots
and post lots of pictures, okay?
Actually, just so you know, Nerissa,
Genta on the drums is the one who played
for our original song, OVERRIDE!
Oh my god! Thank you! Arigato!
Oh my god! Thank you! Thank you!
Genta-san, thank you! Amazing!
So awesome, really appreciate you, thank you.
So many wonderful band members and guests,
I feel very lucky and privileged.
And lucky to have you here, thank you Nerissa.
Do you want to drink a water before we start?
That's a great idea, let's do that.
Immediately. Yes.
Okay, yay, I think we're ready
for another song then, how about that?
I am too! Let's do it!
Okay, together we can do anything! Yes!
Next up is Calliope original song...
...Please enjoy, Orpheus.
Orpheus
Lyrics: Mori Calliope / Music: Koichi Tsutaya
Arrangement: Koichi Tsutaya, Kazuma Nagasawa
[Song: Orpheus]
Lyrics: Mori Calliope / Music: Koichi Tsutaya
Arrangement: Koichi Tsutaya, Kazuma Nagasawa
All right! Thank you so much Nerissa
for coming to hang out! Let's finish this off
with a bang! Here we go!
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though
My heart's beating to your song (oh yeah)
Thinking hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
(Show me what you really wanna do!)
Another late night, aimless dreaming
The day to day starts to call
Still got like a million deadlines
Still bleeding red wine, my back up against the wall
I got my headphones on, walk home is long
Dragging feet like I'm born to lose
'Til somehow they're tapping along
To you-know-who's song
A melody I can't refuse
I'm outta line, but it's fine, you don't know my name
Safe inside my own mind, I don't feel the shame, okay?
I know I get a little carried away
But we got music when there aren't any words to say!
Cuz in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way
Gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
Now I'm in distress, you got me possessed,
I might be obsessed,
So let me get a little something off my chest
Look, I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though
My heart's beating to your song (oh yeah)
Thinking hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
(Show me what you really wanna do!)
Tonight, it's my turn to show you
how obvious I can be
Sometimes it feels like you're playing that guitar
for me and only me
Critics so loud, so predictable,
they can't see what I can see
You're gonna wind up a star
You got me dancing so bizarre
This distance got me feeling fonder, I wonder if it's enough
Cuz I'm not lying when I'm implying
you're all that I've been thinking of
Maybe they'll call me delusional
Baby, this could be real love?
Give me one chance and I'll take
You make me dance the night away
(Get Us Help) (GUH!!)
Now it's a game that I've played before
But with the way the scene changed
there is nothing you can blame me for
I'm talking TV screens, magazines,
seen you in a couple dreams
Pictures up on every padded wall and floor
You're always talking 'bout 'no time to desire a lover'
So why'd you paint your nails up
in my favorite color?
I gotta add it up soon, just when it comes to you
See, our reality is kind of slipping out of tune
I'm ever lost in the groove of somebody new
If it's a function you're after, I'm staying true
So are you noticing me noticing you noticing me?
Not disillusioned but there's not a lot of guarantee
Yes, in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way
Gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
You're strumming next to me and I'm in ecstasy
And for the rest of the week, I'm depression-free!
All right!
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though
My heart's beating to your song (oh yeah)
Thinking hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
(Show me what you really wanna do!)
Tonight, it's my turn to show you
just how obvious I can be
So just as long as you keep playing that guitar...
Critics so loud, so predictable,
they can't see what I can see
You're gonna wind up a star
You got me dancing so bizarre
This distance got me feeling fonder, I wonder if it's enough
Cuz I'm not lying when I'm implying
you're all that I've been thinking of
Maybe they'll call me delusional
Baby, this could be real love?
Give me one chance and I'll take
You make me dance the night away
All right everybody!
Today we have a very special band
that's gathered today.
They're so cool! Right!
We gotta give them a proper introduction, Nerissa.
Yes, we do! So let's do it!
Are you guys ready to meet the band?
Here we go!
First up on the drums, we got Genki!
Drums 白川 玄太
[Drums: Genki Shirakawa]
Then on the bass, it's Yu Park!
Bass / MP Yu Park
And on the guitar, it's Yoshi!
Guitar 芳賀 義彦
[Guitar: Yoshihiko Haga]
And last but not least, tonight's manipulator is Hana!
Manipulator 大場 映岳-hana-
[Manipulator: Hana]
All right Nerissa, let's take 'em out!
Sounds good! Here we go!
Orpheus, get me going, take me space with the bass and the judgment!
So let's blow this joint and if the feelings fight then we can make a little music of our own tonight. Come on!
Why you walking away? I got a lot to say. Guess I'll save up for the next one.
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though my heart's been into us.
Oh yeah? So hear me out, Orpheus, I'm thinking next time I'll show you what I really want to do.
Bye Nerissa! Thanks for singing with me!
Have a good rest of your birthday live!
Yes! See you later! Love you too, bye-bye!
ねえ あたしいつも勇気が足りないから
Hey, I always lack the courage,
自分を大切にできないんだ
so I can't take care of myself.
痛い目をみないと気付けやしないんだ
I don't realize it unless I get hurt.
あーあ 今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, today it's caramel pain again.
Caramel Pain
[Song: Caramel Pain]
良い子でなんかいられないよ
I can't stay a good girl.
だって世界はこんなにも極彩色で
Because the world is so full of vivid colors,
甘ったるくて苦いし
it's sugary sweet and bitter.
あ、待って頭痛いし
Ah, wait, my head hurts,
ヘトヘトで漂うだけの 24/7
just drifting around exhausted, 24/7.
ギリギリ感情おさえるなんてもう無理
I can't keep my emotions in check anymore.
このままではいられないの日々
In these days where I can't stay like this.
ちょっとこわいけど
It's a little scary, but...
置いてくよ 置いてくよ 置いてくよ
I'm leaving it behind, leaving it behind.
今まで手にしたイデオロギーもスタイルも
The ideologies and styles I've held onto,
壊れちゃっても 今がいいよ
even if they break, this moment is better.
だってあたしはあたしのままでずっといたいんだもん
Because I want to stay as myself forever.
ルート？ ムード？ どうでもいーよ
Route? Mood? I don't care about any of it.
トゥーザネクスト もっと危ないことしたら勝ちなんでしょ
To the next, it's a win if you do something riskier.
何を犠牲にしたってしょうがないんだよ
It can't be helped, no matter the sacrifice.
フロムマイベッド この胸の痛みだけ抱いて
From my bed, holding only this pain in my chest.
あーあ 今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, today it's caramel pain again.
ミルフィーユみたいにはぐらかしたって
Even if I dodge it like a mille-feuille,
いつかバレちゃうよ 腐っちゃうよ
it'll be found out eventually, it'll rot away.
痛いとか素直に君に言えてれば
If I could have told you honestly that it hurts,
今頃何か変わってたのかもね
maybe something would have changed by now.
好きなアニメもなくなっちゃうし
Even the anime I love will disappear,
好きな人だっていなくなっちゃうんだ
and the people I love will be gone too.
寂しくなっちゃうな
It makes me so lonely.
大切なことは ただ一つだけさ
There's only one thing that's important.
もう後悔しないように 前を向いて生きるということ！
To live looking forward so I won't regret anything!
置いてくよ 置いてくよ 置いてくよ
I'm leaving it behind, leaving it behind.
今まで手にしたイデオロギーもスタイルも
The ideologies and styles I've held onto,
汚れちゃっても 気にしないよ
even if they're stained, I don't care.
だってあたしはあたしに恋してたいんだもん
Because I want to be in love with myself.
愛してるよ 愛してるよ 愛してるよ
I love you, I love you, I love you.
さよならなんて涙が出ちゃうけど
A goodbye makes the tears come out, but...
何を犠牲にしたってしょうがないんだよ
it can't be helped, no matter the sacrifice.
フロムマイベッド この胸の痛みだけ抱いて
From my bed, holding only this pain in my chest.
あーあ 今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, today it's caramel pain again.
ねえ あたしいつも勇気が足りないから
Hey, I always lack the courage,
自分を大切にできないんだ
so I can't take care of myself.
痛いくらいなら 少し我慢するんだ
If it's going to hurt, I'll just bear it a little.
あーあ 今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, today it's caramel pain again.
Yay! Suisei-senpai is here!
Yeah! The best!
We did it!
It's been a while, but welcome!
Happy Birthday!
Thank you! Please introduce yourself.
A shooting star, a diamond in the rough! Idol vtuber Hoshimachi Suisei!
Calliope, Happy Birthday!
Thank you so much! It's my birthday!
And it's also your 4th anniversary since your major debut!
That's right! Wow, 4 years, it's been a long time. Thank you!
It's amazing! We sang together!
Yeah, four years ago!
メジャーデビューした時のライブで一緒に歌わせてもらいましたね。
We got to sing together at the live for our major debut, didn't we?
懐かしい。
How nostalgic.
ね、懐かしい。
Yeah, nostalgic.
これ、なんかこんなんもやってなくない？
Hey, don't you want to do something like this?
やりました。たくさんやりました。
We did. We did it a lot.
やばいよね、めっちゃいい思い出ですよ。
It's crazy, right? It's such a great memory.
ね、覚えててくれたね、それ。
Yeah, you remembered that.
久しぶりに歌えて嬉しいね。
It's nice to be able to sing it after a long time.
懐かしいポイント。
Nostalgic point.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
そうですね、今回「Caramel Pain」一緒に歌いました。
That's right, we sang "Caramel Pain" together this time.
一番好きな星街すいせい曲です！
It's my favorite Hoshimachi Suisei song!
わー、嬉しい！イェーイ、やったー！
Wow, I'm so happy! Yay, I did it!
めっちゃいい感じだったね、ハモリとかもね。
It felt really good, the harmonies and everything.
ありがとう。たくさん練習しました。
Thank you. We practiced a lot.
ねー、本当に綺麗だったぜ。
Yeah, it was really beautiful.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ちなみに、ほら、ピカピカストーン！
By the way, look, a shiny stone!
Wow, beautiful!
素敵ですよね。
It's lovely, isn't it?
So taking!
So captivating!
え、すいせい先輩。あたし知ってるけど、誕生日はいつですか？
Um, Suisei-senpai. I already know, but when is your birthday?
私は3月の22！
Mine is March 22nd!
March 22! March 22! そうですね。
March 22! March 22! That's right.
せん、せん、せんげつ？
Last... last... last month?
そう、先月！
Yes, last month!
Yes! ですので、ほら、アクアマリンが誕生石で...
Yes! So, look, Aquamarine is your birthstone...
アクアマリンだ！
It's Aquamarine!
もうぴったりよね。私知らなかったよ、自分の誕生石アクアマリンって。
It fits perfectly. I didn't know my birthstone was Aquamarine.
そう、ぴったりですよ。マジで最高。
Yes, it fits perfectly. Seriously the best.
同じ色だよ、もう。
It's the same color already.
同じです！
It's the same!
最高だぜ。
It's the best.
めっちゃ素敵ですよ。めっちゃ綺麗から、一緒に写真撮りましょう！
It's so lovely. It's so beautiful, let's take a photo together!
あ、撮ろう！いいですか？
Oh, let's! Is it okay?
Let's go! Let's go! Yeah!
私ね、やりたいものある。
I have something I want to do.
Okay, what?
これわかる？何のポーズか。
Do you know what this is? What pose this is.
No, ジョジョじゃない？
No, isn't it JoJo?
違うよ。What's this?
No it's not. What's this?
GOLDEN BOWL!
そう！
Right!
これかっこいいよね。
This is cool, isn't it.
ありがとう。Thank you so much. え、ちゃんと見てくれた。ありがとう。
Thank you. Thank you so much. Um, you actually watched it. Thank you.
もちろん！大好きな曲ですよ。
Of course! It's a song I love.
Thank you so much, Senpai. え、ちなみに、everybody really quick before we keep going, お知らせあります！
Thank you so much, Senpai. Um, by the way, everybody really quick before we keep going, I have an announcement!
Yes! Quick announcement about members only! メンバー限定アンコールがありますよ！
Yes! Quick announcement about members only! There's a members-only encore!
やったー！
Yay!
A solo session, and we need to pick one song that I just performed with the amazing guests, and I'm gonna do a solo version of it. Yes!
So you have one minute starting now!
1分ありますよ！投票！
You have one minute! Vote!
あの、カリオペはソロで歌いますよ。
Um, Calliope will sing solo.
さっきゲストと一緒に歌った曲、please vote!
The songs she just sang with the guests, please vote!
Everybody you have one minute, go!
選んでね！この後のメン限でソロで歌ってくれるらしいですよ。
Please choose! Apparently she'll sing solo during the members-only stream after this.
Yes!
えー、全部聴きたいよ！
Eh, I want to hear them all!
そうだね。全部めっちゃめっちゃいい曲、全ての。やばいよ。
That's true. They're all really, really good songs, all of them. It's crazy.
でも、1曲だけ。Only one!
But, only one song. Only one!
ね、1曲だけですよ。選んでくださいね。
Yeah, only one song. Please choose.
選んでね、please, お願いします。
Please choose, please, I beg you.
どれがいいかな、どれがいいかな。Okay, お願いします。
I wonder which one's good, I wonder which one's good. Okay, please.
あー、楽しみ。頑張ります。
Ah, I'm looking forward to it. I'll do my best.
ね。
Yeah.
いや、カリオペ本当にね、4...4年？
No, Calliope, really... 4... 4 years?
メジャーデビューして4年。本当に駆け抜けてきたよね。
It's been 4 years since the major debut. We've really run through it, haven't we?
そう、色々やってますよ。
Yes, we're doing all sorts of things.
なんかアニメのタイアップとかもね、たくさん決まって。
Like anime tie-ups and stuff, a lot of them have been decided.
来ました。来ました。
They came. They came.
So my dream...
ね、嬉しい。
Yeah, I'm happy.
そうですね、夢が叶えた。
That's right, the dream came true.
イェーイ！
Yay!
すごい！めっちゃ嬉しい。
Amazing! I'm so happy.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
皆さんのおかげで。素敵な先輩のおかげでも。
Thanks to everyone. And thanks to my wonderful senpai too.
My inspiration. Thank you so much, everybody.
イェーイ！
Yay!
Yay! So keep shooting for the moon. Yeah.
そうだよ。うん。
That's right. Yeah.
Oh, let's see. Oh, okay. Well, everybody's writing what they want. Oh, okay, すごいすごい。
Oh, let's see. Oh, okay. Well, everybody's writing what they want. Oh, okay, amazing, amazing.
今好きな曲...
The songs you like now...
おー、すごいすごい！本当にね。わー、すごい！Many many many many!
Oh, amazing, amazing! Really. Wow, amazing! Many many many many!
投票がまだまだ...
The voting is still going...
Go, go, go! Choose, choose, choose! 選んで、選んで！選んだ？
Go, go, go! Choose, choose, choose! Choose, choose! Did you choose?
始めて...始めている？投票もう少し長くやりますってよ。
It's started... it's started? They say they'll keep the voting open a little longer.
うん、オッケー。
Yeah, okay.
A little bit longer. Longer, longer time.
Yes, please choose one. It's hard, 難しいと思うけど。Yeah.
Yes, please choose one. It's hard, I think it's difficult. Yeah.
Eh, let's drink water.
あ、確かに。水乾杯？いいですか？
Ah, certainly. A water toast? Is it okay?
飲みましょう。はい。オッケー。うん。
Let's drink. Yes. Okay. Yeah.
チア！ CHEERS!
CHEE-A! CHEERS!
Thank you Senpai. Japanese "Cheers" 何だと思う？
Thank you Senpai. What do you think the Japanese for "Cheers" is?
うん、乾杯。乾杯。
Yeah, kanpai. Kanpai.
最近の流行りなんて言うと思う？
What do you think the recent trend is called?
Um, Cheers?
ケーピー！ KP!
KP! KP!
そうね。え、たくさん使いたいと思う。
Right. Um, I want to use it a lot.
使ってください。乾杯だけでKP。KP! KP!
Please use it. KP just for kanpai. KP! KP!
Hey hey. パリピポが使ってますよ。
Hey hey. Party people are using it.
パリピポ！カリオペパリピじゃないけど、使えます。使えます。
Party people! Calliope is not a party person, but you can use it. You can use it.
Pari-pi-poo in the house let's go! はい。
Party people in the house let's go! Yes.
いいね。Nice.
It's good. Nice.
All right, is the voting closed?
どうかな、どうかな。決まったかな、決まったかな。
I wonder, I wonder. Is it decided, is it decided?
決まったかな？ちょっとわかんない。
Is it decided? I'm not sure.
どうですか皆さん？「お水おいしい」だって。おいしい？
How is it everyone? They're saying "The water is delicious". Is it?
Okay. Oh, close? Oh...
Okay. Oh, closed? Oh...
フワモコ！
FuwaMoco!
フワモコ見てくれてる！
FuwaMoco is watching us!
Thanks for coming! I love FuwaMoco!
今からスタート？
Starting now?
今からスタート。
Starting now.
Okay, no problem.
Push, push! Go, go, go!
ちなみに、カリオペの他のお知らせがあるんだけど。
By the way, Calliope has another announcement.
Oh! カバー曲もリリースします。
Oh! I'm also releasing a cover song.
Yes, check it out! The cover song is...
“In My Head” by なとり。
“In My Head” by NATOLI.
Check it out! In my head...
I like song.
I like that song.
You like it? Me too.
In my head... please listen to it. 聴いてくださいね。
In my head... please listen to it. Please check it out.
そう、あの、このライブの後、そしてその後は…
Right, so, after this live, and after that...
メンバーズ限定！
it's members-only!
Yes!
And we have goods!
Goods are going to be released very soon.
So I wanted to tell you guys... グッズもありますので。
So I wanted to tell you guys... we have goods too.
Limitedもありますので。ちゃんとお伝えしたかったけど、
We have limited editions too. I wanted to tell you properly, but...
最後の方、配信の最後の方はCM流します。
at the end, at the end of the stream, we'll show a commercial.
But in about two minutes...
本当にすぐ出るから、そのURL、
It's coming out really soon, so that URL,
準備しといて。準備して。
get it ready. Be ready.
Ready? 心も準備して。
Ready? Get your heart ready too.
Oh, check it out! Here they are!
えーかっこいい！
Wow, so cool!
Dark Fantasy Calliope!
Dark Fantasy!
Thank you! I'm so cool.
すごい！あの、魔王みたい。
Amazing! You're like... a Demon King.
Yes! 魔王 is English なに？
Yes! What's 'Maou' in English?
魔王…あー、なんて言えばいいかな？
Maou... um, how should I say it?
Dark... Dark King?
Dark King!
英語うまいよ、すごい！
Your English is so good, amazing!
あ、投票終了！
Ah, voting is over!
Voting is over! It's done!
Yay! Thank you so much.
Oh my god, I'm excited to see what you guys chose.
Now then, we should sing one more song then, shouldn't we?
But look out for the goods! URL is dropping soon.
But look out for the goods! The URL is dropping soon.
Limited merch, check that ね。グッズ買って。
Limited merch, check that out. Buy the goods!
よろしくお願いします！
Please do!
Okay! So, あの、たくさん休みましたね。
Okay! So, um, we've rested a lot.
Let's sing one more song!
もう一曲、一緒に歌いたいと思います。
I'd like us to sing one more song together.
いいですか、皆さん？
Are you ready, everyone?
いいですか？
Are you ready?
Ok, じゃあ、二人ならやれるさ。
Ok, well then, if it's the two of us, we can do it.
Next song is... Gold Unbalance.
Gold Unbalance feat. 中島健人
[Title: Gold Unbalance feat. Kento Nakajima]
不確かな物語に 勝ち取るはアイデンティティー
In an uncertain story, I'll seize my identity
あれやこれと 手を替え品を替え
This and that, changing hands and tactics
ドキりと胸を刺す激情
A passion that pierces my heart with a throb
感情はノンフィクションで 喜怒哀楽
Emotions are non-fiction: joy, anger, grief, and pleasure
一心同体 一切合切の衝動
Two bodies, one soul, every single impulse
失敗も成功も味わえ
Savor both failure and success
我らゴールデンバディ
We are Golden Buddies
意味なんてないような世界で 偶然を重ねた光
In a world that seems meaningless, a light of stacked coincidences
脈打つ鼓動 誰にもなれない 言葉を紡いでよ
A pulsing heartbeat, spin the words that no one else can
舐めんじゃねーよ 小さな勇気ひとつありゃ十分
Don't underestimate me, one small spark of courage is enough
強気に高みへと
Confidently, towards the heights
圧倒 絶頂 二人ならやれるさ
Overwhelming, peak, if it's the two of us, we can do it
Back-to-back, no matter what
背負ったもん武器に変わるSpot
The things we carry turn into weapons in this spot
段違い 遠くまで飛ばすShout
On another level, sending our shout far away
誰も邪魔できねぇこのRout
No one can block this route
1等2等3通りって はなからLoser
1st, 2nd, 3rd options? You're a loser from the start
うざいくらい貪欲に ハート地獄からかっぱらっちまえ
Greedy enough to be annoying, snatch your heart from hell
Loop輪廻じゃない Routeは無限に
It's not a loop of reincarnation, the routes are infinite
ありふれた道じゃない 荊の道を好む玄人
Not a common road, a pro who prefers the path of thorns
盛大にもう 笑えばいいさ
Just laugh out loud
才能煩脳のグラデーション
A gradation of talent and worldly desires
どうせならぐちゃぐちゃにしてよ
Might as well make a total mess of it
始めたのならやり切る覚悟を
If you've started, have the resolve to see it through
敗者と勝者のDuet
A duet of losers and winners
劣等感 弾き出された不条理の屑
Inferiority complex, scraps of rejected irrationality
振り払え貪欲に
Shake it off greedily
志は消えない 二人ならやれるさ
Our ambition won't fade, if it's the two of us, we can do it
生きるってなんだ サボった者勝ちか そんなもの
What is living? Is it a game where those who slack win?
握りつぶせ 上辺じゃいられない
Crush it, I can't stay on the surface
エンタメライダー 人生賭け 駆け抜け
Entertainment Rider, betting my life, running through
絶望も栄光も Lemme see you fight back
Despair and glory, let me see you fight back
どうなったって何も変わらないんだって
They say nothing changes no matter what
ミームされた現実に囚われて
Trapped in a memetic reality
This life where we're stuck taking chances
飽き飽きしてんでしょ？？
You're tired of it, aren't you?
We're living in a world with no direction
Reach out with our light 'till we make a connection
Tearing the walls apart
Facing it all, side by side
Once again, it's us against the world
舐めんじゃねーよ
Don't you underestimate me!
本能をヒリつかせて
Letting my instincts tingle,
本物見せつけろ
I'll show them the real thing!
圧倒　絶頂
Overwhelming, at the peak,
アンバランスを踊れ
dance the unbalance!
踊れ
Dance!
Thanks for watching everybody!
Thank you to my guest, thank you to the band,
thank you everyone!
Thank you to my guest, the band, and everyone!
Come hang out at members gentei!
Come hang out at the members-only stream!
OK, この後もよろしく！
OK, see you there too!
Yeah, and 5 is good.
That's about all you guys, I'm Mori Calliope.
That's about all for now, guys. I'm Mori Calliope.
Peace out, see ya!
Let's go, yeah! Bye.
Heh, what's up you crazy skeletons... (coughs)
I mean, dearest Dead Beats,
the hour is finally upon us.
The sale of Mori Calliope's birthday
celebration goods is about to begin.
On this most auspicious day, you've been
granted a great blessing by Death herself.
A most fortunate occurrence for thee that such a
glorious chest should appear before thine eyes.
Let's take a peek at what the Goddess of
Death herself has to offer, shall we?
The journey ahead is long and arduous.
It would do thee good to prepare for it
with such luxurious treasures.
Firstly, wouldst thou find comfort
in Dear Death's embrace?
If it be so, take some warmth along thy
journey with this very large rollable blanket...
...featuring a most intimidating
and battle-ready maiden.
Yours truly!
Designed by my favorite dark fantasy
artist, Shimhaq!
The maiden in question possesses artworks
en masse from this particular individual...
...so I'd be most elated if you
bought it for yourself.
Lay it across your bed, hang it on your
wall, take it with you on an outing...
Think of the possibilities!
Secondly, whilst on thy noble journey, thou
mayest come to need a spark of aid.
If it be so, take one of these amulets.
The emblem of a Knight to boost your Strength.
The emblem of a Samurai to grant
you additional Dexterity.
The emblem of a Priestess to bestow
additional Health to thy weary body.
And lastly, the emblem of a Necromancer
to grant thee additional Intelligence.
Alas, as Fortune be a fickle mistress, thou
may only receive one in a set.
I pray thee be granted the boon most
favorable to thy quest.
Or, or you could just purchase them all separately
if you're looking to speedrun the experience.
Thirdly, I present to thee the shining
centerpiece of this valuable collection.
Take a moment of repose and sit beside
this warm and healing light...
...granted unto thee by Death herself.
A lantern to revive thee as many times as needed
throughout even the most daunting of journeys.
May it light thy way to victory, or to
sweet dreams, whichever is preferred.
Enjoy an elegant design chosen
specifically by myself.
And of course, how could one continue a journey
into vast lands without a source of healing?
Rejuvenate thyself with this generous flask,
or rather glass...
...that seems to refill endlessly upon
rest at your lantern.
At least, I think it will.
There really are no guarantees, but give it a
try yourself, see if the myths are true.
Enjoy your favorite beverage during a night
of exploring your favorite fantasy scenarios.
But naturally, it would do me no good to leave
thee without, I don't know, a bedtime story?
To put this enchanting collection into context.
So, please enjoy a short audiobook-style recording
of a fantastical story, written by yours truly.
Believe it or not, we are the stars of this tale.
So enjoy it on a rainy evening, wrapped
warmly in Death's embrace.
The, the blanket, I mean.
You can use the flask also for like
drinking at the same time.
I don't know, just, you should
really buy the full set.
And definitely do, because lucky skeletons who
act fast and purchase the entire set...
...will be granted a hand-signed postcard...
...with a special color variant of Shimhaq's
masterpiece rendition of Death herself.
The hand-signed option is in limited supply,
so you must be swift.
For those that are unable to secure this extremely
rare offering in time, do not fret.
By purchasing the entire set, a duplicated foil-
stamped signature postcard will be sent.
That is all from me, Death's Maiden and
Dark Fantasy Enjoyer, Mori Calliope.
This year's goods are very different, but I wanted
to pay tribute to a genre that I love so dearly.
And has really made every day of
my job so wonderful and happy.
I am so grateful to you guys for coming
to enjoy my show as well.
Comment and let me know what
your favorite part was.
Be sure to like the concert so
others may be recommended it.
And subscribe if you enjoy Mori Calliope.
With that, I bid thee farewell.
And happy birthday to me!!
Happy Birthday to me!!
6 birthdays huh?! This time was even more special...
[Text: Happy Birthday to me!!
6 birthdays huh?! This time was even more special...]
#UncutRock
Happy Birthday to me!!
6 birthdays high?! This time was even more special
than usual.
Much love to my guests, my Dead Beats, my band,
and everyone who wants to see me fly!
Let's have an even happier year...
together!!
Mori Calliope